Raja Simha K

UX Designer / Web Developer

Arakkonam, Tamilnadu. +91 9047874143 | rajasima58@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/raja-simha-karunagaran/

UX designer with 2+ years of experience crafting engaging, user-friendly dashboards and websites. Skilled in Figma and Adobe tools, I collaborate with 3+ teams to deliver accessible, visually appealing, and user-centered experiences that drive results.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SECURENEXT SOFTWARES

Oct 2024 - Present

UX Designer

- Researched the Competitive Analysis and industry trend analysis, and ideated Problem Statement by interviewing stakeholders for more than 2 Webpage.
- Hand drawn the Story board, Information Architecture, and User Flow for the modern website which has helped in creating 6 problem statement for the user retention.
- Through Brainstorming I have customized navigation menu, feedback modal, interactive contact form, newsletter to improve the Conversion Rate by 30%.

UI Designer

- Collected the Mood board for the Web Design Aesthetics and Graphic Elements which enhanced 60% of the website aesthetics.
- Redesigned the old website into modern website on FIGMA by creating the Brand Style Guide and High Fidelity mockup which reduced the total time taken to 20% by reusability of components.
- Designed the Project Management Dashboard Mockup with more than 10 pages including tables, kanban, Form input, Activity List components within 1 Week.
- Designed the Kanban page for the pre existing CRM
 Dashboard page in 1 day with 90% match to their design system and aesthetics.

Web Developer

- Developed more than 15+ website using HTML, SCSS,
 JavaScript, Bootstrap framework, Wordpress, DIVI for more than 4+ industry and domains.
- I have also worked on the **GSAP**, and Lenis on my personal portfolio to create interactive modern website animations.
- Increased website performance above 90% on **Google page speed** by optimizing for 2+ website and more than 20+ pages.
- Collaborated with the SEO team to enhance site architecture and search crawl efficiency, resulting in 60% improved search engine visibility and ranking.
- Developed the **Dashboard** using the **Sneat theme**, and provided support to the frontend angular team with 4 people which uplifting the Web Accesiblity by 30%.
- I have edited the The Motion Graphic video for our company using Adobe after effects, Premiere Pro, Illustrator.

INTERNSHIP

Designer Intern

Securenext Softwares Dec 2021 - May 2022

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Electrical and Electronic Engineer

Rajalakshmi Engineering College 2017 - 2021

SKILLS

- User Interface (UI) Design
- Usability Testing
- Interaction Design
- Strong Visual Design
- Responsive Design
- · Web Application Design
- Design Systems and Guidelines
- Cross-functional Collaboration
- Design Thinking
- Adobe Creative Suite (Illustrator, Photoshop, XD, Premier Pro, After Effects)
- Figma
- HTML, CSS, jQuery.
- Agile/Scrum Methodologies
- User Experience (UX) Design
- Information Architecture
- User Flow Creation
- · User-centered Design
- · Wireframing and Prototyping
- Motion Graphics
- Image Manipulation and Editing